All my friends and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course in this video,
we are going to implement and create doubly link and list.
So how to create and java that w link last.
We have seen this, this coding and the lectures before, and we are going to implement it in real coding
program in order to execute more and more complex things and algorithms.
So let's begin and we are going to use this data structured the link, at least in the next core exercises
and next videos in order to make things about them, like exercises like methods.
And so.
So let's go here and intelligent idea our or any or any program that runs Java and compile the Java
programs create in you.
Go to the source folder, create new Java class, and I will name this Java class as doubly doubly.
Make it list.
OK.
So if I open this source folder, I have a link and less double link, at least file.
And I will allow the.
If I go to the settings.
I go to the editor.
Or Ed in general, and I put here that think about change font size with control measures apply and
in order to allow the zooming of their code when I click on control and scroll a mouse.
OK, so this is better now, as I told you, in order to create a link, at least double link at lest
we start by creating its own note.
So it's similar to the single single list, but here we have a an extra point there, which refers to
the previous.
So I will create a class note class note here and.
I will often
and I put the data, I will make a double link at least that contains end of data of type and you can
manipulate the characters strings or or any other objects.
But now I I love working with End because it's very, very healthy and very like, very similar and
simpler for a new learner to learn and demonstrate things using numbers.
OK, so I will create A..
This is warfare.
As for previous and note, this is the point of for next in singly linked list we have seen and data
and known next.
The thing that we introduced in the double link, at least, is that reference to the previous note.
OK, now I will create the constructor to it, constructor.
This constructor will be no the same as the class and the look and.
And.
I put data equal to.
The I will prefer putting a data here, so I can put this this data.
This data are equal to data.
OK, so till now, we have finished the no the class and we we are going to use it and the next videos
and we have created that, that look.
Of the first look of that link, at least now I will create a general note in jail, no object called
head, OK.
Inside this class, it contains a class, an anaesthetic class.
And we have an object of this class called no, there's named as hat.
OK, so.
Let's start making that addition, that insertion, pushing, removing and so.
OK, now let's allow to create a method that allows the pushing adding a new node at the front of their
list.
First of all, I will create a method called public, OK?
And this is, let me name it, as exercise or exercise.
No, I think it is 56 public void bush.
This is the method that adds adding he knows.
At the front
of the list.
So I need from you to complete this push method.
And give me the solution and that comment below.
We have created the note.
We have created a double link at last.
And we are going to push now the notes and start making the double link ad lists.
OK.
So I am waiting.
Your your solutions.
Your recommendations.
Any questions or any doubts?
And I am less.